redsharknews.com 2019-12-31

# RedShark News - Privacy & cookie policy

RedShark is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our [Terms of Use](https://www.redsharknews.com/terms-of-use)) sets out how we collect, store and process any personal information that we gather through our website, or that you provide to us directly. Please read this policy carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it.

By visiting this website or providing your personal information to us, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

We may change this privacy policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page frequently to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 25th May 2018.

For the purpose of the _General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679_ , the data controller is Business League Limited (T/A RedShark), Clifton House, Basingstoke, RG21 7JE, United Kingdom.

### Information we may collect about you

##### We may collect and process the following information about you:

##### Information you provide to us

You may provide us with information by filling in forms on our website or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail, live-chat or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register for an account, request a quote, enter into a contract for the supply of services, enter a competition, promotion or survey and when you report a problem with our site. The personal information you provide may include your name, address, e-mail address, phone number, age, job title, personal interests, preferences, financial and credit card information and other information about yourself to enable us to provide you with services or software products. By providing us with this information, you expressly consent to our use of your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy.

##### Information we collect about you

When you visit our website we may automatically collect information about your computer, including your IP address, information about your visit, your location, your browsing history, and how you use our website. This information may be combined with other information you provide to us, as described above.

### What we do with the information we gather

##### We require this information to understand your needs and interests and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * internal record keeping
  * to improve our products and services
  * to send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided
  * to contact you occasionally via email, phone, fax or mail
  * to customise our website according to your interests

### How we use your personal information

##### We use personal information about you in connection with the following purposes:

##### Fulfilling your requests:

  * to provide you with news, information, products and services that you request from us
  * to complete any transaction that you are undertaking with us
  * to administer any promotion that you enter via our website
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so

##### Marketing:

  * to provide you with information about goods and services we or our partners offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about
  * to provide you with information about goods or services that may interest you
  * to measure or understand the effectiveness of advertising we serve to you and others, and to deliver relevant advertising to you, which may be based on your activity on our website
  * to make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may interest you, which may be based on your activity on our website

##### Service Improvements and account management:

  * to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you
  * to administer our site and for internal business administration and operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes
  * to notify you about changes to our service and to send you service emails relating to your account
  * as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure
  * to manage and operate your account with us

### Where we store your personal information

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored in, a country outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. The laws in some countries may not provide as much legal protection for your information as in the EEA. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

##### How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Cookies allow websites to respond to you as an individual and tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site and to provide interest-based advertising.

A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You may adjust the settings on your browser to refuse cookies but some of the services on our website may not work if you do so.

##### Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

##### Controlling your personal information

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting as part of our service as a news and information provider.

##### Email preferences

If you no longer wish to receive news and promotional emails from RedShark, click the unsubscribe link that’s included at the end of every email.

If you have a Lightworks account, you can control your email preferences for both Lightworks and RedShark mailing lists, here: [www.lwks.com/privacy-policy](https://www.lwks.com/privacy-policy)

Under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679, you have a right to download, modify or delete personal information which we hold about you. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please email [privacy@redsharknews.com](mailto:privacy@redsharknews.com). If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please email us as soon as possible at [privacy@redsharknews.com](mailto:privacy@redsharknews.com) and we will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

Updated: 25th May 2018
